<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yash Mehrotra</title>
    <link>http://example.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yash Mehrotra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coloring supervisor</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2018-02-25-coloring-supervisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2018-02-25-coloring-supervisor/</guid>
      <description>What is supervisor Supervisor is a client/server system that allows its users to monitor and control a number of processes on UNIX-like operating systems.
Why I colored it I use supervisor a lot (the organization I work for uses supervisor a lot), so this meant, time to time I had to do supervisorctl status and read the output.
I was always jealous with the JS folks as they had their pm2[link it] which made things colorful and pretty by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Calm and Index Everything</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2015-07-31-keep-calm-and-index-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2015-07-31-keep-calm-and-index-everything/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally written on lambda.grofers.com
Currently at Grofers we are growing rapidly. And with this rapid-growth comes a huge amount of data. As we all know the (not so) famous saying:
 With great amount of data comes an itching need to analyse it.
 As the size of our data is growing rapidly, we have to analyse the trends that push our product forward.
We use PostgreSQL as our primary datastore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruteforcing Cyberoam</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2015-01-27-bruteforcing-cyberoam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2015-01-27-bruteforcing-cyberoam/</guid>
      <description>This post is about how me and Avijit retrieved multiplie cyberoam username/password combinations using python. This also highlights how vulnerable the system is if you are not using a more secure password . Even the default password given to us by the College are being recycled for many years.
DISCLAIMER Before you read this, I want to clarify that we do not intend to use our findings in any unethical way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>